Loumonth Jack Jr.

Backend Software Engineer

McKinney, TX 75070

469.659.2595 Loumonth.Jack.Jr@gmail.com

Summary

As a forward-thinking Software Engineer, I bring an optimistic spirit and a passion for problem-solving. My expertise in Typescript and Python programming languages, as well as my experience in Automotive Marketing, Ticketing, and Fintech Account Management, make me a valuable asset to any team. I am committed to delivering results quickly and accurately, with a focus on Fintech growth. Highly knowledgeable of GraphQL, I am a certified **Graph Developer** - **Associate** issued by Apollo GraphQL.

Experience

Snap! Mobile / Software Engineer - Lead Backend Software Engineer NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT, Richardson, TX

Responsible for building a user directory microservice that manages users, sessions, and permissions, cookie-based authentication. As lead backend engineer, I am responsible for rebuilding an existing financial management application from python to typescript, while utilizing internal microservices, banking as a service and other third party software.

Keep It Simple Technologies / Software Engineer

APRIL 2021 - NOVEMBER 2021, Plano, TX

Developed code fixes and enhancements to be included in future code releases and patches. Conducted software testing to identify bugs and troubleshoot Kiosk hardware issues before application launch.

360 Intelligent Automation / Software Developer

MARCH 2019 - APRIL 2021, Lafayette, LA

Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings, providing updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements. Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.

Education

University of Louisiana at Lafayette / Associate in Business

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2016, Lafayette, LA

Software

Express | Flask | React | Apollo GraphQL | Vue | Jest | Laravel | Rails | AWS

Python | PHP | Typescript | Ruby

Design Patterns | Data Structures | Algorithms

Kubernetes | Docker | Github Actions

FinTech | AdTech | EventTech

Links

https://github.com/loumonthjack

http://loumonth-jack.local.resumed.website

 $\frac{https://www.apollographql.com/tutorials/certifications/717ff98b-0de0-4bf0-9886-b9c660cce5b}{660cce5b}$